<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA),
Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS)
</origin>
<pubdate>2021</pubdate>
<title>Raster Soil Survey by State</title>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
<publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</publish>
</pubinfo>
<othercit>North Carolina</othercit>
<onlink>https://nrcs.app.box.com/v/soils</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>
This georeferenced soil database is a representation of soil survey work
completed using digital soil mapping methodologies. Where available,
this data represents the most detailed level of soil geographic data
developed by the National Cooperative Soil Survey. The associated data
represents Raster Soil Survey class data, available in the State of North Carolina.

The spatial data rendered in the geodatabase result from Raster Soil Survey -
Project Mapping. Raster Soil Survey is a reference to products of soil survey
work completed using digital soil mapping methodologies.

A 10 meter file geodatabase raster layer aligns with the Gridded
Soil Survey Geographic (gSSURGO) Database. Raster Soil Survey data represents
the most detailed soil survey information for a given area within the Gridded
National Soil Geographic Database (gNATSGO) product. Each cell is assigned a
value corresponding to a single attribute 'MUKEY' in the raster attribute table
to facilitate joins with soil attribute data. Additional information on methods
and standards for Digital Soil Mapping and Raster Soil Survey can be found in
Chapter 5 of the Soil Survey Manual and Part 648 of the National Soil Survey
Handbook.
</abstract>
<purpose>
The Raster Soil Survey was created for use in resource planning and analysis
of soils data. The Raster Soil Survey depicts the understanding of soil spatial
variability and the distribution of soil properties and classes beyond
traditional constraints of scale and order in SSURGO. The Raster Soil Survey map
and associated data were prepared by soil scientists as part of the National
Cooperative Soil Survey.
</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>2021</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>publication date</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>As needed</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-84.018296</westbc>
<eastbc>-82.683686</eastbc>
<northbc>35.889267</northbc>
<southbc>34.920600</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>soil survey</themekey>
<themekey>soils</themekey>
<themekey>raster</themekey>
<themekey>Geospatial Data Gateway</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
<placekt>USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</placekt>
<placekey>North Carolina</placekey>
<placekey>Raster Soil Survey</placekey>
</place>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>

The U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation
Service, should be acknowledged as the data source in products
derived from these data.

This soil survey product does not contain detailed site-specific
information and is not designed for use as a primary regulatory
tool in site-specific permitting decisions. Soil Survey Information
is public information and may be interpreted by organizations, agencies,
units of government, or others based on their own needs; however,
users are responsible for the appropriate application of soil survey
information. NRCS will not accept reassignment of authority for
decisions made by other Federal, State, or local regulatory bodies.
NRCS will not make changes to Official Soil Survey Information or of
any supplemental soil mapping for purposes related solely to State
or local regulatory programs.

Digital data files are periodically updated and amended. Files are
dated, and users are responsible for obtaining the latest version
of the data.
</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USDA/NRCS National Soil Survey Center</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
<address>USDA Natural Resources Conservation Service</address>
<address>100 Centennial Mall North</address>
<city>Lincoln</city>
<state>Nebraska</state>
<postal>68508-3866</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>402-437-5499</cntvoice>
<cntfax>402-437-5336</cntfax>
<cntemail>hotline@lin.usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<attracc>
<attraccr>
The attribution is confirmed by display of the map data using
the geospatial and tabular software, in review selected attributes
and spatial relationships. All attribute data conform to the attribute
codes in the Raster Soil Survey Project correlation document.
</attraccr>
</attracc>
<logic>
Descriptive attributes (tabular information about the raster) were developed
specifically for the Raster Soil Survey Projects referenced in this Raster
Soil Survey Area. The classes or Map Units defining the soil survey area
are distributed seamlessly across natural landforms over a broad
physiographic area, or provide detailed soil information in areas without
digital soil survey data in SSURGO as part of progressive soil survey.
</logic>
<complete>
Completeness of maps across the area of interest was assured.
A Raster Soil Map Unit is spatially represented by a 10 meter cell
assigned to a class (Soil Map Unit). A Soil Map Unit
is composed of the entire population of soil components found within.
</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>
The accuracy of these digital data is based upon the sourced digital
environmental data references outlined in the Raster Soil Survey Project
correlation. Positional accuracy is referenced as spatial tolerance
for the project accuracy assessment outlined in the Raster Soil Survey
Project correlation document accessed at the online refences cited in
the lineage.
</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
<pubdate>2021</pubdate>
<title>Published Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) databases.</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
<publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>online</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>2021</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>NRCS1</srccitea>
<srccontr>source of project extent</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>USDA/NRCS National Soil Survey Center</origin>
<pubdate>2021</pubdate>
<title>Gridded Soil Survey Geographic (gSSURGO)</title>
<geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
<publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>online</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>2021</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>NRCS2</srccitea>
<srccontr>source of project extent</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>USDA/NRCS National Soil Survey Center</origin>
<pubdate>2021</pubdate>
<title>Published Raster Soil Surveys</title>
<geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
<publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>online</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>2021</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>NRCS3</srccitea>
<srccontr>source of project extent</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>USDA/NRCS National Soil Survey Center</origin>
<pubdate>2021</pubdate>
<title>Raster Soil Survey Project correlation document</title>
<geoform>metadata - prediction and model evaluation</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubplace>
<publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>online</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>2021</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>NRCS4</srccitea>
<srccontr>source of project documentation</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
<pubdate>2021</pubdate>
<title>National Soil Information System (NASIS) data base</title>
<geoform>tabular digital data</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Fort Collins, Colorado</pubplace>
<publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>database</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>2021</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>NASIS</srccitea>
<srccontr>attribute (tabular) information</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<procstep>
<procdesc>
This dataset consists of georeferenced digital map data
and computerized attribute data. The National Soil Information
System (NASIS) database was developed by NRCS soil scientists
according to national standards. The Raster Soil Survey Map Units
are linked to attributes in NASIS. A statewide file geodatabase (ESRI)
was created using ArcGIS software to accommodate the spatial
and tabular Raster Soil Survey data. Spatial and tabular data is packaged
in a standard product consistent with the delivery of USDA-NRCS Gridded
Soil Survey Geographic Database (gSSURGO). All structural
and attribute metadata for SSURGO also applies
to Raster Soil Survey data. gSSURGO is similar to
the standard USDA-NRCS SSURGO Database product but
in the format of an Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc.
(ESRI®) file geodatabase.
</procdesc>
<srcused>NRCS1, NRCS2, NRCS3, NASIS</srcused>
<procdate>2021</procdate>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>
Classification and correlation is documented in the NASIS database
for specific projects referenced in this dataset. Data development
aligns with the stages and processes for Digital Soil Mapping projects
as outlined in Chapter 5 of the Soil Survey Manual. Data development,
and validation documentation may be cited referencing the 'laoverlap'
table (Legend Area Overlap) - Legend Area Overlap Type: Raster Soil
Survey Project. Raster Soil Survey Project correlation document
contains supporting documentation for referenced projects. Documenation
can be accessed below cited state under 'DSM Raster Soil Survey (RSS)
Projects' at the online linkage: https://tinyurl.com/rwbbgj2
</procdesc>
<srcused>NASIS, NRCS4</srcused>
<procdate>2021</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Raster</direct>
<rastinfo>
<rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
</rastinfo>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
<horizsys>
<planar>
<mapproj>
<mapprojn>NAD_1983_Contiguous_USA_Albers</mapprojn>
<albers>
<stdparll>29.50000000</stdparll>
<stdparll>45.50000000</stdparll>
<longcm>-96.0000</longcm>
<latprjo>23.00000000</latprjo>
<feast>0.0000</feast>
<fnorth>0.0000</fnorth>
</albers>
</mapproj>
<planci>
<plance>coordinate pair</plance>
<coordrep>
<absres>10.000000</absres>
<ordres>10.000000</ordres>
</coordrep>
<plandu>meters</plandu>
</planci>
</planar>
<geodetic>
<horizdn>GCS_North_American_1983</horizdn>
<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
<denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
</geodetic>
</horizsys>
</spref>
<eainfo>
<overview>
<eaover>
Relevant attributes are the cell soil values. Raster cell locations are
representative of Map Units developed from soil survey projects completed
using digital soil mapping methodologies. Field investigations were conducted
to infer the relationships between observed soil descriptions and spatially
explicit environmental data. The Map Unit key (MUKEY) is used to link to information
in the National Soil Information System (NASIS) tables.
</eaover>
<eadetcit>Relevant attributes are the cell soil values.</eadetcit>
<eadetcit>
Soil Survey Staff, 2014. Keys to Soil Taxonomy, 12th ed. USDA-Natural
Resources Conservation Service, Washington, DC.

U.S. Department of Agriculture. National soil survey handbook, title 430-VI.
Soil Survey Staff, Natural Resources Conservation Service.

Soil Survey Staff, 2017. Soil survey manual (Ag. Handbook 18).
USDA-Natural Resources Conservation Service, Washington, DC.

U.S. Department of Agriculture. (current issue).
National Soil Survey Handbook, title 430-VI.
</eadetcit>
</overview>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service,
National Geospatial Center of Excellence
</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
<address>501 West Felix Street</address>
<city>Fort Worth</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postal>76115</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>800-672-5559</cntvoice>
<cntfax>817-509-3469</cntfax>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<resdesc>Raster Soil Survey Database State of North Carolina</resdesc>
<distliab>
Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer
system at the U.S. Department of Agriculture, no warranty expressed
or implied is made by the Agency regarding the utility of the data
on any other system, nor shall the act of distribution constitute
any such warranty. The U.S. Department of Agriculture will warrant
the delivery of this product in computer readable format, and will
offer appropriate adjustment of credit when the product is determined
unreadable by correctly adjusted computer input peripherals, or
when the physical medium is delivered in damaged condition. Request
for adjustment of credit must be made within 90 days from the date
of this shipment from the ordering site.

The U.S. Department of Agriculture, nor any of its agencies are
liable for misuse of the data, for damage, for transmission of
viruses, or for computer contamination through the distribution of
these datasets.

The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) prohibits discrimination in
all of its programs and activities on the basis of race, color,
national origin, age, disability, and where applicable, sex,
(including gender identity and expression), marital status, familial
status, parental status, religion, sexual orientation, political
beliefs, genetic information, reprisal, or because all or part of an
individual's income is derived from any public assistance program.
(Not all prohibited bases apply to all programs.) Persons with
disabilities who require alternative means for communication of
program information (Braille, large print, audiotape, etc.) should
contact USDA's TARGET Center at (202) 720-2600 (voice and TDD).

To file a complaint of discrimination, write to USDA, Assistant
Secretary for Civil Rights, Office of the Assistant Secretary for
Civil Rights, 1400 Independence Avenue, S.W., Stop 9410,
Washington, DC 20250-9410, or call toll-free at (866) 632-9992
(English) or (800) 877-8339 (TDD) or (866) 377-8642
(English Federal-relay) or (800) 845-6136 (Spanish Federal-relay).
USDA is an equal opportunity provider and employer.
</distliab>
<stdorder>
<digform>
<digtinfo>
<formname>ESRI File Geodatabase</formname>
<formcont>spatial</formcont>
<transize>65 MB</transize>
</digtinfo>
<digtopt>
<onlinopt>
<computer>
<networka>
<networkr>https://nrcs.app.box.com/v/soils</networkr>
</networka>
</computer>
</onlinopt>
</digtopt>
</digform>
<fees>
There is currently no direct charge for requesting data or for
retrieval via FTP.
</fees>
<ordering>Call or write to organizations listed under Distributor.</ordering>
</stdorder>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20211101</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
<address>National Soil Survey Center</address>
<address>100 Centennial Mall North</address>
<city>Lincoln</city>
<state>Nebraska</state>
<postal>68508-3866</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>402-437-5499</cntvoice>
<cntfax>402-437-5336</cntfax>
<cntemail>hotline@lin.usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
